<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>English on Sergio Olmos</title>
    <link>/categories/english/</link>
    <description>Recent content in English on Sergio Olmos</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/english/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to eurolig</title>
      <link>/post/2019-11-28-introduction-to-eurolig/introduction-to-eurolig/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-11-28-introduction-to-eurolig/introduction-to-eurolig/</guid>
      <description>eurolig provides a toolkit to easily retrieve and analyze basketball generated data for the Euroleague with R. The package is mainly designed to work with two types of data: play-by-play data and shot location data. Although Euroleague’s first season was in 2000, play-by-play and shot location data is only available since the 2007/2008 season. This post introduces the latest realease of the package (v0.4.0) and shows how it could be used to do some basic analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing FC Barcelona&#39;s assists pattern</title>
      <link>/post/2019-03-28-eurolig/analisis-asistencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-03-28-eurolig/analisis-asistencia/</guid>
      <description>Introduction eurolig is an R package that I just created for obtaining and analyzing basketball data games from the Euroleague. In this post I show how to use the package to analyze different aspects of the way FC Barcelona passes the ball in this Euroleague 2018-2019. More specifically, we are interested in finding out:
What type of shot each assist generates
 How many points are being generated by each assist</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recamán&#39;s sequence</title>
      <link>/post/2019-02-20-la-secuencia-de-recaman/la-secuencia-de-recaman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-02-20-la-secuencia-de-recaman/la-secuencia-de-recaman/</guid>
      <description>Take a look at the following sequence of numbers:
\[0, 1, 3, 6, 2, 7, 13, 20, 12, 21, 11, 22, \ldots\]
If you have not seen it before, you probably will not be able to figure out the pattern in this sequence. It is the so called Recamán’s sequence, attributed to the Colombian mathematician Bernardo Recamán.
Despite its apparent complexity, the rules that generate this sequence are quite simple. The best way to understand the generating algorithm is to draw the number line from 0 to, say, 7 to start:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rfeb: Shot charts with R</title>
      <link>/post/2019-01-24-graficos-de-tiro-con-r/shotcharts-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-01-24-graficos-de-tiro-con-r/shotcharts-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Kirk Goldsberry is one of the most popular figures in the basketball analytics world. He is known mainly for the use of shot charts in his analyses. Here there is an example with all the shots Lebron James has taken in his career:
Happy Birthday, LeBron His constellation so far... pic.twitter.com/4HuCjTgl4x
&amp;mdash; Kirk Goldsberry (@kirkgoldsberry) December 30, 2018  Shot charts can be useful for, say, identifying tenedencies on offense of a given player/team, showing what spots on the court a player is most effective at, or analyzing what type of shots a team allows its opponents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the multiplication table with R</title>
      <link>/post/2018-11-06-multiplication-table/multiplication-table-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-11-06-multiplication-table/multiplication-table-with-r/</guid>
      <description>I was reading about the Hidden beauty of multiplication tables and I thought it could be fun to make some of the cool plots in that article with R.
As I was trying to visualize new patterns in the multiplication table, I ended up with some useful fuctions that I decided to put in a simple R package called multable that you can install from GitHub.
The multiplication table Consider the standard \(10 \times 10\) multiplication table, with the first row and the first column taking the values \(1\) through \(10\), forming a grid with the corresponding products.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>