<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Mínimos Cuadrados</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Mínimos Cuadrados</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>rfeb: Shot charts with R</title>
      <link>/post/2019-01-24-graficos-de-tiro-con-r/shotcharts-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-01-24-graficos-de-tiro-con-r/shotcharts-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Kirk Goldsberry is one of the most popular figures in the basketball analytics world. He is known mainly for the use of shot charts in his analyses. Here there is an example with all the shots Lebron James has taken in his career:
Happy Birthday, LeBron His constellation so far... pic.twitter.com/4HuCjTgl4x
&amp;mdash; Kirk Goldsberry (@kirkgoldsberry) December 30, 2018  Shot charts can be useful for, say, identifying tenedencies on offense of a given player/team, showing what spots on the court a player is most effective at, or analyzing what type of shots a team allows its opponents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the multiplication table with R</title>
      <link>/post/2018-11-06-multiplication-table/multiplication-table-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-11-06-multiplication-table/multiplication-table-with-r/</guid>
      <description>I was reading about the Hidden beauty of multiplication tables and I thought it could be fun to make some of the cool plots in that article with R.
As I was trying to visualize new patterns in the multiplication table, I ended up with some useful fuctions that I decided to put in a simple R package called multable that you can install from GitHub.
The multiplication table Consider the standard \(10 \times 10\) multiplication table, with the first row and the first column taking the values \(1\) through \(10\), forming a grid with the corresponding products.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>